James McCarthy

951-262-5142 james@jmgalleries.com

SUMMARY

Passionate and creative Full-Stack Web Developer and designer with UX experience. Lives in a makers world, crafting responsive websites from wire-frame to release using stable and modern languages and frameworks including React, PHP, Perl and MySQL to Javascript and HTML/CSS.

Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, XML, JSON, Perl, PHP7 and familiar with Node.js. **Frameworks**: React, Codelgnitor, Drupal, Bootstrap, Yahoo YUI, Material UI, TWIG, Smarty,

jQuery, SASS/LESS, Normalize, Foundation, Wordpress and familiar with Laravel. **Version Control**: Git/Bitbucket, Microsoft TFS/VSS and familiar with Perforce.

Web Server Environments: LAMP, Apache, Nginx, Windows IIS and familiar with Node.js.

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, and familiar with Mongo and SQL Server.

Methodologies: Agile/Scrum and Waterfall.

Project Management Tools: Jira, MS Project, ServiceNow and Basecamp.

EXPERIENCE

MY DAILY CHOICE, FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER, 6/2020 - CURRENT

Currently contributing to the development of multiple MY DAILY CHOICE public facing e-commerce websites, as well as the company's "Back Office" admin tools for affiliates and inside sales and marketing teams.

- Back-End (80%): Perl, MySQL and Cloudflare.
- Front-End (18%): Javascript +jQuery, Vue, HTML/CSS (SASS) and Bootstrap(3/4)
- UI/UX (2%): Adobe InDesign, Photoshop and Figma.

CONTRACT WEB DEVELOPER, 1994 - Current

Have consulted with companies, including, Thermofisher Scientific (2020), University of Nevada System for Higher Education, California State University Sacramento, Microsoft, Intel, Cirrus Systems (2015), and University of Nevada School of Medicine.

- Back-End (45%): PHP3-7, .Net, AWS, Apache, NGINX, Perl, git, VSS, MySQL and Postgres.
- Front-End (45%): Javascript +jQuery, Vue, React, TWIG, and HTML/CSS (SASS, LESS).
- UI/UX (10%): Sketch, Invision, Figma, Adobe XD and Principal.

CAESARS ENTERTAINMENT, USER EXPERIENCE ENGINEER, 8/2018 — 1/2020

Created wire-frames, high-fidelity mock-ups and prototypes for Caesars Entertainment brands 16+ properties. Also, collaborated with Chicago-based consultancy, Bounteous, on caesars.com redesign as well as interactive agency, Verb, on Caesars Entertainment property page templates. Guided a UX team of 5 designers and product owners through user-experience workshops and facilitated lunch-and-learn UX sessions with product owners providing coaching of Nielson Norman User Experience best practices. Established a Design System Manager using InVision to standardize style guide for internal and contract designers and developers.

- Back-End (5%): Adobe AEM, git and Jira, Agile/Scrum.
- Front-End (5%): Javascript +jQuery, React, HTML/CSS (SASS) and Bootstrap(4).
- UI/UX (95%): Sketch, Invision, and Principal.
- Training: Nielson Norman Group, UX Training, 6 credits

BARRICK GOLD, FRONTEND DEVELOPER, 6/2017 — 8/2018

Created low-fidelity wire-frames for an application to automate the creation and maintenance of FMEAs (Failure Modes and Effects Analysis). Also, worked with an Agile Barrick team, Microsoft consultants and data scientists to build a proof-of-concept, web-based predictive analytics application for Barrick Gold Nevada Gold mine sites Cortez and Gold Strike using React and Redux frameworks.

- Back-End (5%): .Net, Node.js, git/bitbucket, Jira and Agile/Scrum.
- Front-End (90%): React with Redux, Material UI, Javascript +jQuery, HTML/CSS (SASS).
- UI/UX (5%): Sketch, Invision, and Balsamiq.
- Certification: Scrum of Scrums Training, Scrum Inc.

HANGER, INC, SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER, 1/2016 - 6/2017

Worked on development and maintenance of proprietary accounting and inventory system written in PHP and PostgreSQL that was used by sales staff and executive management. Also, wrote a PHP CLI script to scrape Medicare data for rehabilitation centers and insert into PostgreSQL database used by Sales team to generate sales leads.

- Back-End (90%): PHP, MySQL, Postgres and git.
- Front-End (10%): Javascript +jQuery, Yahoo YUI, HTML/CSS (SASS).

VSP GLOBAL, DIGITAL MARKETING SPECIALIST, 4/2013 - 2/2015

Worked on front-end UI UX design, development and maintenance of Member, Client and Broker Portals, including white-labeled sites for MetLife, Cigna, Sight for Students and Blue Shield. Responsible for wire framing, mocking-up design using Adobe Creative Suite applications, prototyping with Protoshare, creating A/B tests using Optimizely and coding of functional elements in JavaScript +jQuery and Magnolia CMS. Maintained miscellaneous Wordpress Blog websites.

- Back-End (5%): Java, Magnolia CMS, Perforce, git, Jira and Agile/Scrum.
- Front-End (90%): Javascript +jQuery, HTML/CSS (SASS/LESS) and Bootstrap(2).
- UI/UX (5%): Prototype, Adobe Photoshop/InDesign, Protoshare and Balsamiq.

ODDS ON PROMOTIONS, SENIOR WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPER, 6/2011 - 8/2012

Designed and developed Odds On Promotions content management system and consumer-facing website in PHP Codelgniter framework, javascript and interfacing with a MySQL database. Creative was delivered by graphic artist and coded from Adobe Photoshop PSD and InDesign files. SEO Optimization for site and automation of Facebook contests coordinated with Social team.

- Back-End (75%): PHP, MySQL, .Net, Microsoft SourceSafe (VSS)
- Front-End (20%): Javascript +jQuery, HTML/CSS (SASS).
- UI/UX (5%): Adobe InDesign and Photoshop.

QUINSTREET MEDIA, WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPER, 10/2008 - 2/2011

Supported the editorial department content production system, social media department facebook development as well as b2b, education, medical and military verticals. Also maintained corporate Drupal powered website and various Wordpress blogs.

- Back-End (45%): PHP (Drupal, Codelgnitor, Wordpress), MySQL, Java and Perforce.
- Front-End (45%): Javascript +jQuery, HTML/CSS (SASS).
- UI/UX (5%): Adobe InDesign and Photoshop.

TWELVE HORSES, WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPER, 10/2006 - 2/2008

Supported multiple clients in an agency environment, including Nevada Humanities Online Nevada Encyclopedia, City of Sparks, Reno/Sparks Convention & Visitors Authority, Las Vegas Monorail and Scolaris Grocers. Primarily a back-end development LAMP stack.

- Back-End (75%): Apache, PHP, PostgreSQL, Perl, Excel and Basecamp (Project Management).
- Front-End (25%): SMARTY, Javascript, HTML/CSS and Wordpress.

TARSIN, INC, BRAND DESIGNER, 02/2006 — 10/2006

Worked under the direction of the Creative Director co-branding product marketing collateral, mobile software and website design, including wire-frames, Flash apps and web-apps for national brands Motorola, CarPhone Warehouse, Cellular One, VOCE, Kodak, Sony Ericsson, Radio Shack, and AT&T.

- Back-End (5%): Java and ServiceNow (Project Management)
- Front-End (93%): HTML/CSS, Adobe Flash (ActionScript) and Javascript.
- UI/UX (2%): Adobe Photoshop and InDesign.

NEVADA SYSTEM FOR HIGHER EDUCATION, INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT III, 10/1998 — 02/2006

Provided state-wide support to faculty and staff for information technologies including workshops for faculty, student, staff as well as created the first Online Distance Education catalog for NSHE.

- Back-End (50%): Windows IIS/XP (WIMP Stack), Perl, MySQL, PHP and MS Project.
- Front-End (47%): HTML/CSS and Javascript.
- UI/UX (2%): Adobe Photoshop and InDesign.

WEBSCAPES, OWNER, 12/1994 — 10/1998

Started a small business specializing in website design, system administration, content management and creation using LAMP stack as well as Perl, PHP, Javascript, HTML/CSS. Design comps were created using with Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator and InDesign.

EDUCATION

1996 University of Nevada, Reno — Bachelor's degree English, minor Journalism

PORTFOLIO & LINKS

Github https://github.com/sjamesmccarthy LinkedIn https://linkedin.com/in/jmccarthyusa

Case Studies, Portfolio https://jmccarthyusa.com Fine Art Photography https://jmgalleries.com